Abby Bigaouette

Graphic designer and journalist based in Tahlequah, Oklahoma. Well versed in photography, publication layout, social media outreach, and video production. Has experience in project management, interviewing, publication distribution, web development/design, advertising, and inventory & shipping management.

Education

Tahlequah High School

August 2018 - May 2022

- 3.05 GPA
- PLTW Engineering and Cisco Networking courses completed.

Experience

Graphic Designer | Tahlequah Daily Press

August 2022 - Present

- Designs pages for daily publication under tight deadlines using Adobe InDesign, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, and BLOX Total CMS.
- Manages production and design of magazines, tabloids, and ads.
- Writes Q&A interview format stories quarterly for Green Country Scene, a magazine focused on local artists, musicians, and events.
- Successfully streamlined magazine portfolio and rebooted Tahlequah Grapevine, a quarterly community variety magazine last published in the early 2010s.

High-Power Rocketry | Hobby

July 2019 - Present

- Meshes 3D printing and conventional contruction methods to dramatically reduce the cost to build and fly high power rockets.
- Has flown a rocket twice in a 24-hour poriod demonstrating structural soundness and rapid reusability.
- Obtained National Association of Rocketry Level 1 certification.
- Creates mission patches for flights and test campaigns.

Digital Artist & Photographer | Self Employed

May 2017 - Present

- Works across Autodesk Fusion 360, Blender, and Serif Affinity suite.
- Prints and ships high quality 3D printed parts to international customers.
- Uses versatile photography skills to capture portraits and astrophotography.

Chief Media Editor | Tahlequah High School Yearbook

August 2021 - June 2022

- Developed branding for the Tahlequah HS Yearbook Instagram account.
- Led multiple successful outreach and advertising campaigns on Instagram leading to record- breaking sales in the 2021-2022 school year.
- Managed team scheduling for event coverage and ad design.

Contact Information

Based in Tahlequah, OK email: abby@bigaouette.com phone: (918) 506-1265

Skills

Adobe CC Suite

- · Publication layout
- Vector graphics
- · Photo editing
- Video editing

Serif Affinity Suite

- Publication layout
- Vector graphics
- Photo editing

Photography

- Portraits
- Athletics
- Astrophotography

Communication

- Copywriting
- Interviewing
- Data visualization

3D Modeling & Printing

- Autodesk Fusion 360
- Drafting
- Ultimaker Cura
- Prusaslicer

Computer Skills

- Office 365 and alternatives
- Highly proficient in the use of Windows, macOS, and Linux
- Figma, JS, HTML, and CSS

Certifications

Level 1 Certification

National Association of Rocketry July 2023

Volunteering

Recovery Team

Hot Nozzle Śociety July 2023